Korman, Gerd, Files /4226
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Gerd Korman Files
1834-1987
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Korman, Gerd
/4226
3.5 cubic feet
3.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
8055512
Biographical / Historical
Professor Emeritus of American History at Cornell University ILR School
Gerd Korman is a professor emeritus of American History at Cornell University's ILR School. His books include the prize-winning Industrialization, Immigrants, and Americanizers and several works that established him as an early student of the Holocaust, including the anthology Hunter and Hunted.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3012: Alice Cook Papers
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 16, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Korman, Gerd.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8055512
- Jewish Labor Leaders. Names and Affiliations, 1936-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Manuscripts from Israeli Archives, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Hebrew or Yiddish and English
- Manuscripts from Israeli Archives, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Hebrew or Yiddish, English, German
- Manuscripts from Israeli Archives, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  German, Yiddish or Hebrew, and English
- Manuscripts from Israeli Archives, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Manuscripts from Israeli Archives, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Yiddish or Hebrew, German, English
- Manuscripts from Israeli Archives, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Hebrew or Yiddish, English
- Manuscripts from Israeli Archives, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  English and Hebrew (and possibly Yiddish)
- Manuscripts from the Israeli Archives, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  German, English and Hebrew
- Manuscripts from the Israeli Archives, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  German, English, and Hebrew or Yiddish
- Manuscripts from Israeli Archives, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  German, English, Hebrew or Yiddish
- Manuscripts from the Israeli Archives, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Israeli Archives. Vaad Hapoel, 1924-1948 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Hebrew or Yiddish
- Va'ad Hapoel, 1928-1937 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Israeli Archives, 1930-1932 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  German, English and Hebrew or Yiddish
- Israeli Archives, 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  English
- Israeli Archives, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Israeli Archives, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  English, German and Hebrew or Yiddish
- Josef Shapiro and Miriam Getter. Chaim Arlosoroff, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Hebrew
- Zionism Notebooks (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Nationalism, Ethnicity, Zionism and Arabs; Research Notes
- Israeli Archives. Ben Gurion., 1919-1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  1919-1923, 1970. English and Hebrew
- Israeli Archives. Weitzmann, 1919-1921 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Hebrew and English
- Israeli Archives. Ben Zvi, 1924-1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Israeli Archives. Efal, Mereminski, 1927-1944 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  English and Hebrew
- Israeli Archives. Beit Berl, 1934-1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Israeli Archives. Va'ad Hapoel, 1925-1930 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Israeli Archives. Beth Lessin, Aaron Rabinowitz, 1901-1945 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Israeli Archives, 1910-1921 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Israeli Archives, 1925-1929 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Israeli Archives, 1923-1924 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Amalgamated Manuscripts, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Amalgamated Manuscripts, 1939-1947 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Am. Jewish Comm. - Jews in Nazi Germany, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Schlossberg Journalist Papers - General, 1914-1943 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Schurman Manuscript, 1926-1931 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Amalgamated Manuscripts, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Zionism Reprints, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Arlozoloff 1928 (cassettes) (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Amalgamated Manuscripts, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Minutes of the General Executive Board Meeting, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Montreal, Windsor Hotel, June 11 - 13 1921
- Preservation Copies. Minutes of the General Executive Board Meeting, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Minutes of the General Executive Board, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Hotel Morrison, Chicago, December 20 - 23 1921
- Minutes of the Meeting of the Extraordinary Session of the General Executive Board, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  October 6 - 8 1921
- Social Welfare Programs of the Amalgamated Union Cooperative Housing, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  by Norma Burke
- 'Labor Education in the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America: Education for Mobility or Class?", 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Jay Hoffman
- "The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America: An Investigation of the membership through Advance 1917-1921", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Stephen Binhak
- Minutes of the General Executive Board Meeting, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Pennsylvania Hotel, New York. July 7 1920
- meeting of the General Executive Board, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  June 14 - 20 1923
- Meeting of General Executive Board. Preservation Copy, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Meeting of General Executive Board, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Hotel Morrison, Chicago. December 27 - 30 1923
- Preservation copy. Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  December 27 - 20 1923. Hotel Morrison, Chicago, Illinois
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  St Paul Minnesota. November 10 - 13 1924
- Preservation Copy. Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Minutes of the General Executive Board, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  May 3 1922
- Preservation Copy. Minutes of the General Executive Board, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Memorandum on the Meeting of the New York Board Members, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  January 5 1922
- Minutes of the Meeting of the New York Board Members and Memorandum, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  New York. January 24 1922
- Correspondence of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1916-1918 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Correspondence of Sidney Hillman, 1919-1920 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Correspondence of Sidney Hillman, 1921-1927 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Sidney Hillman Manuscripts and Notes (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Routine Correspondence, 1913-1925 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Correspondence of Sidney Hillman, 1911-1919 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Correspondence of Sidney Hillman, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Management Documents, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Newspaper Clippings, Notes and Correspondence, 1916-1921 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- "The Boat People" AFL Issues, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University
- Arbitration, 1950-1955 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Arbitration, 1951-1977 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  1951-1955, 1977
- Religion and the Labor Movement OHA (Box 7, Folder 31)
- "American Protestantism and a Jewish State", 1973 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  Hertzel Fishman
- Knights of Labor. Copies (Box 7, Folder 33)
  1882
- Coat Seaman's Journal (Box 7, Folder 34)
- United Mine Worker's Journal (Box 7, Folder 35)
  1890's
- National Trades Union Copies, 1834 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- National Labor Tribune Copies, 1876-1894 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  1876, 1882, 1894